## Kartikrao Jevaji

Denver, CO

Phone: (412) 638-3064 | Email: kartikinpublic@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/kjevaji</u> | GitHub: <u>github.com/nitrotap</u> | Portfolio: <u>nitrotap.dev</u>

### Summary

Full-stack web developer with strong analytical skills and educated at the University of Minnesota Coding Bootcamp. Strong skills in MERN stack with emphasis on JavaScript and Progressive Web Applications. Experienced with non-profits, CRMs, and databases. Excited to apply learned skills to develop cutting-edge applications and open-source software. A self-described Tekno-junkie that loves learning new languages and is driven to build and perfect.

#### Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript, Java, SQL, R (currently learning Python)

**Workflows:** Agile and Waterfall using GitHub/GitLab/Jupyter, Functional and OOP paradigms **Server-side:** Express.js, Node.js/npm, Jest, Heroku, AWS, Apollo, GraphQL, RESTful APIs **Front-End:** React, HTML, JS, CSS, Materialize, jQuery, Material UI (CSS-in-JS), Chart.js

Databases: MySQL, Sequelize, NoSQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Mongoose

**Abilities:** Excellent written communication skills and highly detail-oriented, Organized and comfortable with multiple projects, Able to work closely in a team or independently with progress reports

### **Projects**

#### Mental Health Check | github.com/nitrotap/mental-health-check | mhcheck.app

- A mental health quiz app that helps users track their moods using standardized screening tests.
- Project Leader organizing project, setting up project structure, delegating tasks, fixing merge conflicts and bugs, deployment workflows
- Technologies (MERN stack) MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js/npm, Chart.js, Material UI (CSS-in-JS), Apollo/GraphQL, Heroku, bcrypt, and JSON Web Tokens

# **Traveler's Hidden Gems** | github.com/nitrotap/travelers-hidden-gems | sleepy-woodland-16634.herokuapp.com

- A travel guide to hidden spots across the globe. Find the offbeat, see something interesting, and share it with others!
- Project Leader organizing project, setting up project structure, delegating tasks, fixing merge conflicts and bugs, deployment workflows
- Technologies Node.js/npm, leaflet.js, GeoApify API, bcrypt, Express.js, Sequelize ORM, MySQL, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js, express-cookies, and OpenStreetMaps

## **Experience**

## Data Entry/Tech Support Volunteer Alzheimer's Association

2017 – Current Denver, CO

Critical thinking used to ensure accuracy of key database identifiers

Quick problem solving during education classes providing on-demand tech support virtually

Completed Certification Training for Personify (CRM)

Application Coordinator Epic Systems

2011–2012 Madison. WI

Critical thinking used to coordinate implementation of Willow-Inpatient
Technical competencies and teamwork demonstrated by working with Interface team
Leadership demonstrated providing task management and tracking for build team
Communication used as primary point of contact for all customer-related questions
Providing support internally for internal workflows

#### Education

Full Stack Web Development Certificate: University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN 2022

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Master's in Statistics: University of Pittsburgh, Pittsburgh, PA 2011

Combined BS/MA program, focusing on practical applications of statistics in healthcare, industry, and research. Statistical Consulting across multiple disciplines, and coursework including GLMs, Categorical and Logistical Models, and Experimental Design